<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Developers_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter id="restapi">
	<title>MantisBT REST API</title>

	<para>
		The primary means of integrating with MantisBT with web services is
		with the bundled REST API, which is accessible at

		<literal>https://server.com/mantis/api/rest/</literal>.
	</para>

	<section id="restapi.auth">
		<title>Authentication</title>

		<para>
			REST API calls can be authenticated using one of the following methods:
		</para>

		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>API Token</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The primary authentication method. Create an API token for your user
						account and pass it in the <literal>Authorization</literal> HTTP request
						header.  API token authentication is required when using impersonation.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Anonymous</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						When anonymous access is enabled and an anonymous account is configured,
						the API can be accessed without authentication for read-only operations.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Cookie (Web UI)</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Used internally by the MantisBT Web UI when JavaScript calls the API on
						behalf of an already authenticated user session.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>

	<section id="restapi.impersonation">
		<title>Impersonation</title>

		<para>
			Users with sufficient access (controlled by the
			<literal>$g_impersonate_user_threshold</literal> configuration option, default:
			ADMINISTRATOR) can make REST API calls on behalf of another user.  Typical use
			cases include:
		</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>Reproducing an issue as reported by a specific user</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Testing a user's access to projects, issues, and fields</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Performing operations on behalf of a service account</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<para>
			To impersonate a user, include the <literal>X-Mantis-Username</literal> HTTP
			request header with the username of the target user.  The following constraints
			apply:
		</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The caller must authenticate with an API token (the
					<literal>Authorization</literal> header).  Impersonation is not available
					with cookie or anonymous authentication.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The caller must have the access level defined by
					<literal>$g_impersonate_user_threshold</literal>.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>A user cannot impersonate themselves.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					A user cannot impersonate another user whose access level is higher than
					their own.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The target user must be a valid, enabled user.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<section id="restapi.impersonation.response_headers">
			<title>Response Headers</title>

			<para>
				Every REST API response includes the following informational headers:
			</para>

			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term><literal>X-Mantis-Username</literal></term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The username under which the request was executed.  When
							impersonation is active, this reflects the impersonated user's
							username rather than the caller's.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term><literal>X-Mantis-LoginMethod</literal></term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The authentication method used for the request.  Possible values
							are <literal>api-token</literal>, <literal>cookie</literal>, and
							<literal>anonymous</literal>.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="restapi.postman">
		<title>Postman</title>

		<para>
			Postman is a tool to enable REST API development and collaboration.
			It is used by MantisBT team to share the API definitions
			and enables the community to experiment with the API.

			<ulink url="https://www.postman.com/">Download Postman</ulink>.
		</para>

		<para>
			Once Postman is installed, you should be able to bootstrap it with the
			MantisBT API collection via the MantisBT API documentation posted on Postman.

			<ulink url="https://documenter.getpostman.com/view/29959/7Lt6zkP">Download Collection</ulink>.
		</para>

		<para>
			The MantisBT API Postman collection is also distributed with MantisBT in the
			`api/rest/api.postman_collection.json`. The Postman environment template is also
			available at `api/rest/env.postman_environment.json`.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="restapi.export">
		<title>Exporting Postman Collection</title>

		<para>
			The bundled Postman collection can be updated by clicking on the "..." next
			to "Mantis Bug Tracker REST API" and choosing "Export...". Then select
			"Collection v2.1" and click "Export" and select `api/rest/api.postman_collection.json`.
			Then follow the standard pull request and checkin process.
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
