<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Developers_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="dev.contrib">
	<title>Contributing to MantisBT</title>

	<para>
		MantisBT source code is managed with <ulink url="https://git-scm.com/">Git</ulink>.
		If you are new to this version control system, you can
		find some good resources for learning and installing it in
		<xref linkend="dev.appendix.git" />.
	</para>

	<section id="dev.contrib.setup">
		<title>Initial Setup</title>

		<para>
			There are a few steps the MantisBT team requires of contributors and
			developers when accepting code submissions.  The user needs to configure
			Git to know their full name (not a screen name) and an email address they
			can be contacted at (not a throwaway address).
		</para>

		<para>
			To set up your name and email address with Git, run the following
			commands, substituting your own real name and email address:
		</para>

		<programlisting>
git config --global user.name "John Smith"
git config --global user.email "jsmith@mantisbt.org"
		</programlisting>

		<para>
			Optionally, you may want to configure Git to use terminal colors
			when displaying file diffs and other information, and also
			alias certain Git actions to shorter phrases to reduce typing:
		</para>

		<programlisting>
git config --global color.diff "auto"
git config --global color.status "auto"
git config --global color.branch "auto"

git config --global alias.st "status"
git config --global alias.di "diff"
git config --global alias.co "checkout"
git config --global alias.ci "commit"
		</programlisting>

	</section>

	<section id="dev.contrib.clone">
		<title>Cloning the Repository</title>

		<para>
			The official MantisBT source code repository is hosted at
			<ulink url="https://github.com/mantisbt/mantisbt">GitHub</ulink>.

			This document assumes that you have already signed up for and
			setup a GitHub account.
		</para>

		<section id="dev.contrib.clone.dev">
			<title>Determining the Clone URL</title>

			<para>
				Which URL you will use to clone the repository before you
				start developing depends on your situation.
			</para>

			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>MantisBT Core Team Developers</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							MantisBT developers have <emphasis>push</emphasis> access to the
							official repository.
						</para>
						<para>
							Benefiting from this access requires a special URL
							that uses your SSH key to handle access permissions:
							<literal>git@github.com:mantisbt/mantisbt.git</literal>.
							Alternatively, an HTTPS link can be used as well,
							in which case you will have to provide your GitHub
							User ID and password when Git requests it:
							<ulink url="https://github.com/mantisbt/mantisbt.git">https://github.com/mantisbt/mantisbt.git</ulink>.
						</para>

						<note><para>
							Pushes <emphasis>will fail</emphasis> if you
							do not have access or your public SSH key
							is not set up correctly in your GitHub profile.
						</para></note>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>

				<varlistentry>
					<term>Contributors</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							For other people, the MantisBT repository and
							the related clone URLs
							<literal>git@github.com:mantisbt/mantisbt.git</literal> (SSH).
							or
							<ulink url="https://github.com/mantisbt/mantisbt.git">https://github.com/mantisbt/mantisbt.git</ulink> (HTTPS)
							will always be read-only.
						</para>
						<para>
							It is therefore strongly advised to <emphasis>
							<ulink url="https://github.com/mantisbt/mantisbt/fork">
								create your own fork
							</ulink>
							</emphasis> of MantisBT where you will be able
							to push your changes, and then use the fork's URL
							instead to clone, which will look like this:
							<literal>git@github.com:MyGithubId/mantisbt.git</literal>.
							or
							<ulink url="https://github.com/MyGithubId/mantisbt.git">https://github.com/MyGithubId/mantisbt.git</ulink>
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</section>

		<section id="dev.contrib.clone.clone">
			<title>Initializing the Clone</title>

			<para>
				To clone the repository, execute the following command
				from your target workspace:
<programlisting>
git clone YourCloneURL
</programlisting>
				After performing the cloning operation, you should end up with a new
				directory in your workspace, <filename>mantisbt/</filename>,
				containing the MantisBT repository with a <literal>remote</literal>
				named <emphasis>origin</emphasis> pointing to your Clone URL.
			</para>

			<para>
				MantisBT uses <ulink url="https://getcomposer.org">Composer</ulink>
				to pull libraries and components from <ulink url="https://packagist.org">Packagist</ulink>
				and <ulink url="https://github.com">Github</ulink>.
				<ulink url="https://getcomposer.org/download/">Install Composer</ulink> and run the following
				command:
<programlisting>
composer install
</programlisting>
			</para>

			<warning><para>
				Failure to execute the submodule initialization commands
				will result in critical components being missing from
				<filename>/vendor</filename> folder, which will then
				cause errors when running MantisBT.
			</para></warning>
		</section>

		<section id="dev.contrib.clone.remotes">
			<title>Adding remotes</title>

			<para>
				If you are planning to use your own fork to push and
				maintain your changes, then we recommend setting up an
				<emphasis>upstream</emphasis> <literal>remote</literal>
				for MantisBT's official repository, which will make it easier
				to keep your repository up-to-date.
<programlisting>
git remote add --tags upstream git://github.com/mantisbt/mantisbt.git
</programlisting>
			</para>
		</section>


		<section id="dev.contrib.clone.branches">
			<title>Checking out branches</title>

			<para>
				By default, the new clone will only track code from
				the primary remote branch, <literal>master</literal>,
				which is the latest development version of MantisBT.
				If you are planning to work with stable release or
				other development branches, you will need to set up
				local tracking branches in your repository.
			</para>
			<para>
				The following command will set up a tracking branch for the
				current stable branch, <literal>master-1.3.x</literal>.
<programlisting>
git checkout -b master-1.3.x origin/master-1.3.x
</programlisting>
			</para>

			<note>
				<para>
					With the introduction of submodules for some of the
					third-party libraries, you may encounter
					issues when switching to an older branch which
					still has code from those libraries in a subdirectory
					of <filename>/library</filename> rather than a submodule:
				</para>
				<para>
<programlisting>
$ git checkout old_branch
error: The following untracked working tree files would be overwritten by checkout
	(list of files)
Aborting
</programlisting>
				</para>
				<para>
					To resolve this, you first have to get rid of the
					submodules directories before you can checkout the branch.
					The command below will move all submodules to
					<filename>/tmp</filename>:
<programlisting>
sed -rn "s/^.*path\s*=\s*(.*)$/\1/p" .gitmodules |xargs -I{} mv -v {} /tmp
git checkout old_branch
</programlisting>
				</para>
				<para>
					Alernatively, if you don't care about keeping the changes
					in the submodules directories, you can simply execute
<programlisting>
git checkout -f old_branch
git clean -df
</programlisting>
				</para>
				<para>
					When switching back from the older branch, the submodules
					directories will be empty.
					At that point you can either
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								Update the submodules to reclone them
<programlisting>
git submodule update
</programlisting>
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								Restore the directories previously moved
								to <filename>/tmp</filename> back into
								the empty directories, e.g.
<programlisting>
sed -rn "s/^.*path\s*=\s*(.*)$/\1/p" .gitmodules |xargs -n 1 basename |xargs -I{} mv -v /tmp/{} library
</programlisting>
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
				<para>
					For further reference:
					<ulink url="https://git-scm.com/book/en/Git-Tools-Submodules#Issues-with-Submodules">
						Pro Git book
					</ulink>
				</para>
			</note>
		</section>

	</section>

	<section id="dev.contrib.branch">
		<title>Maintaining Tracking Branches</title>

		<para>
			In order to keep your local repository up-to-date with the
			official one, there are a few simple commands needed for any
			tracking branches that you may have, including
			<literal>master</literal> and <literal>master-1.3.x</literal>.
		</para>

		<para>
			First, you'll need to get the latest information from the
			remote repository:
<programlisting>
git fetch origin
</programlisting>
		</para>

		<note><para>
			If you cloned from your personal GitHub fork instead of
			the official MantisBT repository as explained in
			<xref linkend="dev.contrib.clone.remotes" />,
			then you should instead execute:
<programlisting>
git fetch upstream
</programlisting>
		</para></note>

		<para>
			Then for each tracking branch you have, enter the following commands:
<programlisting>
git checkout BranchName
git rebase
</programlisting>
		</para>

		<para>
			Alternatively, you may combine the fetch and rebase operations
			described above into a single pull command
			(for each remote tracking branch):
<programlisting>
git checkout master
git pull --rebase
</programlisting>
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="dev.contrib.prepare">
		<title>Preparing Feature Branches</title>

		<para>
			For each local or shared feature branch that you are working on, you will
			need to keep it up to date with the appropriate master branch.  There are
			multiple methods for doing this, each better suited to a different type of
			feature branch.  <emphasis>Both methods assume that you have already
			performed the previous step, to update your local tracking branches
			(see <xref linkend="dev.contrib.branch" />).</emphasis>
		</para>

		<section id="dev.contrib.prepare.local">
			<title>Private Branches</title>

			<para>
				If the topic branch in question is a local, private branch, that you are not
				sharing with other developers, the simplest and easiest method to stay up to
				date with <literal>master</literal> is to use the <command>rebase</command>
				command.  This will append all of your feature branch commits into a linear
				history after the last commit on the <literal>master</literal> branch.
			</para>

			<programlisting>
git rebase master feature
			</programlisting>

			<note>
				<para>
					Rebasing changes the ID for each commit in your feature
					branch, which will cause trouble for anyone sharing
					and/or following your branch.
				</para>
				<para>
					The resulting conflict can be fixed by rebasing their
					copy of your branch onto your branch:
				</para>

				<programlisting>
git checkout feature
git fetch remote/feature
git rebase remote/feature
				</programlisting>
			</note>
		</section>

		<section id="dev.contrib.prepare.public">
			<title>Public Branches</title>

			<para>
				For any publicly-shared branches, where other users may be watching your
				feature branches, or cloning them locally for development work, you'll need
				to take a different approach to keeping it up to date with
				<literal>master</literal>.
			</para>

			<para>
				To bring public branch up to date, you'll need to <command>merge</command>
				the current <literal>master</literal> branch, which will create a special
				"merge commit" in the branch history, causing a logical "split" in commit
				history where your branch started and joining at the merge.  These merge
				commits are generally disliked, because they can crowd commit history, and
				because the history is no longer linear.  They will be dealt with during
				the submission process (see <xref linkend="dev.contrib.test" />).
			</para>

			<programlisting>
git checkout feature
git merge master
			</programlisting>

			<para>
				At this point, you can push the branch to your public repository, and
				anyone following the branch can then pull the changes directly into their
				local branch, either with another merge, or with a rebase, as necessitated
				by the public or private status of their own changes.
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="dev.contrib.test">
		<title>Running PHPUnit tests</title>

		<para>
			MantisBT has a suite of PHPUnit tests found in the <literal>tests</literal>
			directory. You are encouraged to add your own tests for the patches you
			are submitting, but please remember that your changes must not break
			existing tests.
		</para>

		<para>
			In order to run the tests, you will need to have the PHP Soap extension,
			<ulink url="http://www.phpunit.de">PHPUnit 3.4 or newer</ulink> and
			<ulink url="http://phing.info">Phing 2.4 or newer</ulink> installed.
			The tests are configured using a <literal>bootstrap.php</literal> file. The
			<literal>boostrap.php.sample</literal> file contains the settings you will
			need to adjust to run all the tests.
		</para>

		<para>
			Running the unit tests is done from root directory using the following
			command:
		</para>

		<programlisting>
phing test
		</programlisting>

		<section id="dev.contrib.test.soap">
			<title>Running the SOAP tests</title>

			<para>
				MantisBT ships with a suite of SOAP tests which require an initial
				set up to be executed. The required steps are:
			</para>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para>Install MantisBT locally and configure a project
					and a category.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem><para>Adjust the <literal>bootstrap.php</literal> file
					to point to your local installation.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem><para>Customize the <literal>config_inc.php</literal>
					to enable all the features tested using the SOAP tests.
					The simplest way to do that is to run all the tests once
					and adjust it based on the skipped tests.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>

		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="dev.contrib.submit">
		<title>Submitting Changes</title>

		<para>
			This section describes what you should do to submit a set of changes
			to MantisBT, allowing the project developers to review and test,
			your code, and ultimately commit it to the MantisBT repository.
		</para>
		<para>
			The actual submission can be done using several methods, described
			later in this section:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis>Recommended:</emphasis>
						Github Pull Requests (see
						<xref linkend="dev.contrib.submit.github" />)
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Other public Git repository Pull Requests (see
						<xref linkend="dev.contrib.submit.repo" />)
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Git Formatted patches (see
						<xref linkend="dev.contrib.submit.patch" />)
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>

		<section id="dev.contrib.submit.before">
			<title>Before you submit</title>

			<para>
				Before submitting your contribution, you should make sure that
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Your code follows the
							<ulink url="https://mantisbt.org/wiki/doku.php/mantisbt:coding_guidelines">
								MantisBT coding guidelines
							</ulink>
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							You have tested your changes locally
							(see <xref linkend="dev.contrib.test" />)
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Your local branch has been rebased on top of the current
							Master branch, as described in
							<xref linkend="dev.contrib.prepare.local" />.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</para>
		</section>

		<section id="dev.contrib.submit.github">
			<title>Submission Via Github Pull Requests</title>

			<para>
				Since the <ulink url="https://github.com/mantisbt/mantisbt">
				official MantisBT repository</ulink> is hosted there, using
				<ulink url="https://github.com">GitHub</ulink> is the
				recommended (and easiest) way to submit your contributions.
			</para>

			<para>
				With this method, you can keep your changesets up-to-date
				with the official development repository, and likewise let
				anyone stay up to date with your repository, without needing
				to constantly upload and download new formatted patches
				whenever you change anything.
			</para>

			<para>
				The process below describes a simple workflow that can help
				you make your submission if you are not familiar with Git;
				note that it is by no means the only way to do this.
			</para>

			<note><para>
				We'll assume that you have already
				<ulink url="https://github.com/mantisbt/mantisbt/fork">forked MantisBT</ulink>,
				cloned it locally as described in
				<xref linkend="dev.contrib.clone" />
				(remote <emphasis>upstream</emphasis> being the official
				MantisBT repository and <emphasis>origin</emphasis> your
				personal fork), and created a new feature branch
				(see <xref linkend="dev.contrib.prepare" />)
				for your contribution, which we'll call
				<emphasis>MyBranch</emphasis>.
			</para></note>

			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Make sure that the <emphasis>MyBranch</emphasis> feature
						branch is up-to-date with the master branch by
						rebasing it, resolving any conflicts if necessary.
						<programlisting>
git fetch upstream
git rebase upstream/master MyBranch
						</programlisting>
					</para>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>
						Push the branch to your Github fork

						<programlisting>
git push origin MyBranch
						</programlisting>
					</para>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>
						Go to your Fork on Github
						(<ulink url="https://github.com/MyGithubId/mantisbt"></ulink>)
					</para>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>
						Initiate a
						<ulink url="https://github.com/MyGithubId/mantisbt/compare/MyBranch">
							Pull Request</ulink>
						from your feature branch, following the guidelines provided in
						<ulink url="https://help.github.com/articles/using-pull-requests">
							Github Help</ulink>.
					</para>
					<para>
						Please make sure you provide a detailed description
						of the changes you are submitting, including the
						reason for it and if possible a reference (link) to
						an existing issue on
						<ulink url="https://mantisbt.org/bugs/">our bugtracker</ulink>.
						The team will usually review your changes and provide
						feedback within 7 days (but your mileage may vary).
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>

		</section>

		<section id="dev.contrib.submit.patch">
			<title>Submission Via Formatted Patches</title>

			<para>
				Formatted patches are very similar to file diffs generated
				by other tools or source control systems, but contain far
				more information, including your name and email address, and
				for every commit in the set, the commit's timestamp,
				message, author, and more.  They allow anyone to import the
				enclosed changesets directly into Git, where all of the
				commit information is preserved.
			</para>

			<para>
				Assuming that you have an existing local that you've kept up
				to date with <literal>master</literal> as described in
				<xref linkend="dev.contrib.prepare" /> currently checked out,
				generating a formatted patch set should be relatively
				straightforward, using an appropriate filename as the target
				of the patch set:
			</para>

			<programlisting>
git format-patch --binary --stdout origin/master..HEAD > feature_branch.patch
			</programlisting>

			<para>
				Once you've generated the formatted patch file, you can easily attach it
				to a bug report, or even use the patch file as an email to send to the
				developer mailing list.  Developers, or other users, can then import this
				patch set into their local repositories using the following command, again
				substituting the appropriate filename:
			</para>

			<programlisting>
git am --signoff feature_branch.patch
			</programlisting>
		</section>

		<section id="dev.contrib.submit.repo">
			<title>Submission Via Public Repository</title>

			<para>
				If you are not able or not willing to make use of a fork of
				the official <ulink url="https://github.com">GitHub</ulink>
				repository but have another publicly available one to host
				your changes, for example on a free hosting for public
				repository such as

				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<ulink url="https://bitbucket.org">Bitbucket</ulink>
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<ulink url="https://gitlab.com">GitLab</ulink>
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>

				you can still use it to submit a patch in a similar fashion
				to the Github method described above, although the process
				is slightly more complicated.
			</para>

			<para>
				We'll assume you've already set up a publicly accessible
				repository at URL <literal>git@githosting.com:contrib.git</literal>,
				kept it up-to-date with MantisBT's official repository,
				and that you have pushed your feature branch
				<literal>MyBranch</literal> to it.
			</para>

			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Generate the Pull Request
					</para>
					<para>
						This will list information about your changes and
						how to access them.  The process will attempt to
						verify that you've pushed the correct data to the
						public repository, and will generate a summary of
						changes.
						<programlisting>
git request-pull origin/master git@githosting.com:contrib.git MyBranch
						</programlisting>
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Paste the output of the above command into a bug report or
						an email to the
						<ulink url="mailto:mantisbt-dev@lists.sourceforge.net">developer mailing list</ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>

			<para>
				Once your pull request has been posted, developers and other users can add
				your public repository as a remote, and track your feature branch in their
				own working repository using the following commands, replacing the remote
				name and local branch name as appropriate:
			</para>

			<programlisting>
git remote add feature  git@githosting.com:contrib.git
git checkout -b MyBranch feature/MyBranch
			</programlisting>

			<para>
				If the feature is approved for entry into MantisBT core,
				then the branch should first be rebased onto the latest HEAD
				so that Git can remove any unnecessary merge commits, and
				create a linear history. Once that's completed, the feature
				branch can be merged into <literal> master</literal>:
			</para>

			<programlisting>
git rebase master feature
git checkout master
git merge --no-ff feature
			</programlisting>

		</section>

	</section>

</chapter>

