<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Admin_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter id="admin.about">
    <title>About MantisBT</title>

    <section id="admin.about.what">
        <title>What is MantisBT?</title>

        <para>
            MantisBT is a web based bug tracking system that was first made
            available to the public in November 2000.  Over time it has matured
            and gained a lot of popularity, and now it has become one of the most
            popular open source bug/issue tracking systems.  MantisBT is developed
            in PHP, with support to multiple database backends including MySQL,
            MS SQL and PostgreSQL.
        </para>

        <para>
            MantisBT, as a PHP script, can run on any operating system that
            is supported by PHP and has support for one of the DBMSes that
            are supported.  MantisBT is known to run fine on Windows, Linux,
            macOS and a variety of Unix operating systems.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="admin.about.who">
        <title>Who should read this manual?</title>

        <para>
            This manual is targeted for the person responsible for evaluating,
            installing and maintaining MantisBT in a company. Typically we refer
            to this person as the MantisBT administrator.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="admin.about.license">
        <title>License</title>

        <para>
            MantisBT is released under the terms of
            <ulink url="https://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html">GNU General
            Public License (GPL)</ulink>.  MantisBT is free to use and modify.
            It is free to redistribute as long as you abide by the distribution
            terms of the <ulink url="https://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html">GPL</ulink>.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="admin.about.download">
        <title>How to get it?</title>

        <para>
            MantisBT is available in several Linux distributions
            including: Debian, Ubuntu, Fedora, Gentoo, Frugalware and others.
            Hence, if you are running Linux, start by checking if your distribution
            has a package for MantisBT.  If not, or if the package is
            not up-to-date with the latest MantisBT version, then you may want
            to download it directly from
            <ulink url="https://mantisbt.org/download.php">here</ulink>.
        </para>

        <para>
            For Windows, macOS and other operating systems, use the link provided
            above to download MantisBT.  The download is compressed in tar.gz
            or zip format.  Both formats can be unpacked using tools like
            <ulink url="https://www.7-zip.org/">7-Zip</ulink> (in case of Windows).
        </para>


        <para>
            Note that at any point in time there are typically two "latest"
            MantisBT releases that are available for download.  The latest
            production release (stable), and the latest development release
            which can be an alpha or a release candidate.  It is not recommended
            to use development releases in production specially if it is still
            in the alpha stage unless the administrator is familiar with PHP
            and is able to troubleshoot and fix any issues that may arise.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="admin.about.name">
        <title>About the Name</title>

        <para>
            When initially seeking to name this project Ken ran into a
            problem every programmer encounters. What is a good name?  It has to
            be descriptive, unique, and not too verbose.  Additionally having
            multiple meanings would be a nice touch.  Quickly
            ruled out were php*Something* names which, incidentally, although
            popular, do not seem to be condoned by the PHP Group
            developers.  Drawing inspiration from Open Source projects like
            Apache, Mozilla, Gnome, and so forth resulted in two eventual
            choices: Dragonfly and Mantis. Dragonfly was already the name of a
            webmail package. So the name became Mantis.
        </para>

        <para>
            Praying Mantis are insects that feed primarily on other insects and bugs.
            They are extremely desirable in agriculture as they devour insects that feed
            on crops. They are also extremely elegant looking creatures.  So, we
            have a name that is fairly distinctive and descriptive in multiple
            ways.  The BT suffix stands for "Bug Tracker" and distinguishes
            this project from general usage of the word Mantis.  However, over
            time the project was typically referred to as Mantis.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="admin.about.history">
        <title>History</title>

        <para>
            Kenzaburo Ito and a friend originally created a bug tracker
            as an internal tool for their pet project. A search for good, free
            packages came up with nothing suitable so they wrote their own.
            After a rewrite and cleanup it was made available to the public via
            the GNU General Public License (GPL). The GPL was chosen partly
            because of his belief that development tools should be cheap or
            free. In 2002, Ken was joined by Jeroen Latour, Victor Boctor and
            Julian Fitzell to be the administrators and the core development
            team of MantisBT. This marks a new era in MantisBT lifetime where it is
            now a team project.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="admin.about.support">
        <title>Support</title>

        <para>
            There are plenty of resources to help answer support queries.  Following
            are the main ones:
        </para>

        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <ulink url="https://mantisbt.org/forums/">Forums</ulink> - The
                    forums are one of the most popular destinations for getting
                    MantisBT support.  Start off by searching the forums for your
                    questions, if not found, then go ahead and submit a question.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <ulink url="http://www.mantisbt.org/mailinglists.php">Mailing lists</ulink> -
                    Several lists are available, each of them with its own,
                    specific purpose.  Note that posting messages is restricted
                    to subscribers so you will have to register before you can
                    send messages; however, there are public archives available
                    if you're only interested in reading.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <ulink url="https://gitter.im/mantisbt/mantisbt">Gitter</ulink>
                    is a browser-based, on-line chat that has mainly replaced the
                    team's use of IRC. In the main chat room, you can have a live
                    discussion with the developers and other MantisBT users.
                    Gitter supports all modern browsers and also offers Android
                    and iOS-based clients, as well as an
                    <ulink url="https://irc.gitter.im/">IRC bridge</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <ulink url="http://www.mantisbt.org/irc.php">IRC</ulink> -
                    The IRC channel not very active anymore, as the developers
                    have moved on to using Gitter for live discussions;
                    nevertheless, the channel is still open.
                    There are many free IRC clients:
                    XChat (for Linux), <ulink url="http://hexchat.github.io/">HexChat</ulink>,
                    <ulink url="http://www.icechat.net/">IceChat</ulink> amongst others.
                    You can also use <ulink url="http://webchat.freenode.net/">Web Chat</ulink>
                    to connect to IRC via your web browser, which may also be useful when
                    you're behind a firewall that blocks the IRC port.
                    The IRC channel logs are archived and made
                    <ulink url="http://www.mantisbt.org/irclogs.php">
                        available on the MantisBT web site</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <ulink url="https://mantisbt.org/wiki/doku.php/mantisbt:start">Wiki</ulink> - The
                    MantisBT Wiki has information related to "How To (recipes)",
                    FAQ, feature requirements, plugins etc.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Search - A good way for locating an answer to your question
                    or finding more information about a topic is to search across
                    all MantisBT website and the Internet via your favorite
                    search engine, e.g.
                    <ulink url="https://www.google.com">Google</ulink> or
                    <ulink url="https://www.bing.com">Bing</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <note>
            <para>Support questions should not be sent directly to MantisBT
                developers or through the MantisBT website's contact pages.
        </para>
        <para>Also, our <ulink url="https://mantisbt.org/bugs/">bug tracker</ulink>
            is reserved for reporting issues with the software, and
            <emphasis>must not be used for support requests</emphasis>.
        </para></note>
    </section>

    <section id="admin.about.news">
        <title>MantisBT News</title>

        <para>
            There are several ways to keep up to date with MantisBT news.  These
            include:
        </para>

        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    We send release announcements and important updates to users registered
                    on our <ulink url="https://mantisbt.org/bugs">official bugtracker</ulink>.
                    To get onto our mailing list, users will have to signup there and verify
                    their email address. This same account can also be used to report, monitor,
                    and comment on issues relating to MantisBT.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <ulink url="https://mantisbt.org/blog/">MantisBT Blog</ulink>
                    is used to communicate announcements about new releases, topics
                    relating to MantisBT, etc.  Users are encouraged to subscribe to
                    the RSS feed to know when new posts are posted there.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <ulink url="https://twitter.com/mantisbt">Twitter</ulink> is used to
                    notify users about up-to-date details about what is happening with MantisBT development.
                    Twitter users are encouraged to follow "@mantisbt".
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section id="admin.about.versioning">
       <title>Versioning</title>

       <para>
           Our release numbering convention follows the guidelines of
           <ulink url="https://semver.org/">Semantic Versioning</ulink>.
           Given a version number <emphasis>Major.Minor.Patch</emphasis>
           and an optional <emphasis>Suffix</emphasis> (eg. 1.3.0-rc.1):
       </para>

       <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                     Major - Indicates a very large change in the core package.
                     Rewrites or major milestones.
                     API changes which are not backwards-compatible.
                </para>
        </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Minor - Introduction of new features or significant changes
                    in functionality, in a backwards-compatible manner.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Patch - Bug fixes, maintenance and security releases.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Suffix - Optional, indicates a development release.
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem><para>
                            a<emphasis>N</emphasis> or
                            alpha.<emphasis>N</emphasis> for
                            alpha releases,
                        </para></listitem>
                        <listitem><para>
                            b<emphasis>N</emphasis> or
                            beta.<emphasis>N</emphasis> for
                            beta releases, or</para></listitem>
                        <listitem><para>rc<emphasis>N</emphasis> or
                            rc.<emphasis>N</emphasis> for release candidates.
                            </para></listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    Absence of suffix indicates a stable release.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
   </section>
</chapter>

