<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
 <!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Admin_Guide.ent">
]>
<section id="admin.config.api">
	<title>API</title>

	<para>MantisBT exposes a webservice API which allows remote clients to interact with MantisBT and perform many of the usual tasks, such as reporting issues, running filtered searches and retrieving attachments.</para>
	<para>
		The SOAP API is enabled by default and available at <literal>/api/soap/mantisconnect.php</literal>
		below the MantisBT root.  A WSDL file which describes the web service is available at
		<literal>/api/soap/mantisconnect.php?wsdl</literal> below the MantisBT root.
	</para>
	<para>
		The REST API is enabled by default.
		A Swagger sandbox and documentation for REST API is available at <literal>/api/rest/swagger/</literal> below
		the MantisBT root.
	</para>

	<para>The following options are used to control the behaviour of the MantisBT SOAP API:</para>
	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_webservice_readonly_access_level_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Minimum global access level required to access webservice for readonly operations.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_webservice_readwrite_access_level_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Minimum global access level required to access webservice for read/write operations.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_webservice_admin_access_level_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Minimum global access level required to access the administrator webservices.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_webservice_specify_reporter_on_add_access_level_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Minimum project access level required for caller to be able to
				specify reporter when adding issues or issue notes. Defaults to DEVELOPER.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_webservice_rest_enabled</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Whether the REST API is enabled or not.  Note that this flag only
					impacts API Token based auth.  Hence, even if the API is disabled, it can still be
					used from the Web UI using cookie based authentication.  Default ON.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>

	<section id="admin.config.api.disable">
		<title>Disabling the webservice API</title>
		<para>If you wish to temporarily disable the webservice API it is sufficient to set the specific access thresholds to NOBODY:</para>
		<para><literal>$g_webservice_readonly_access_level_threshold = $g_webservice_readwrite_access_level_threshold = $g_webservice_admin_access_level_threshold = NOBODY;</literal></para>
		<para>While the SOAP API will still be accessible, it will not allow users to retrieve or modify data.</para>
	</section>
</section>
