<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
 <!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Admin_Guide.ent">
]>
<section id="admin.config.display">
	<title>Display</title>

	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_font_family</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Name of the google font family for the browser to use. For all available fonts, see:
					<ulink url="https://fonts.google.com/">
						fonts.google.com
					</ulink>.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_font_family_choices</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Google font family list offered to the user to chose from. Font files are fetched from google
					servers.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_font_family_choices_local</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This is a small subset of <emphasis>$g_font_family_choices</emphasis> in which font
					files are part of MantisBT installation.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_window_title</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This is the browser window title (&lt;TITLE&gt; tag).
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_search_title</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This is used as prefix to describe Browser Search entries,
					and must be short enough so that when inserted into the
					'opensearch_XXX_short' language string, the resulting text
					is 16 characters or less, to be compliant with the limit for
					the ShortName element as defined in the
					<ulink url="https://github.com/dewitt/opensearch/blob/master/opensearch-1-1-draft-6.md">
						OpenSearch specification
					</ulink>.
				</para>
				<para>Defaults to the value of $g_window_title.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_favicon_image</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Path to the favorites icon relative to MantisBT root folder
					This icon should be of <emphasis>image/x-icon</emphasis> MIME type,
					and its size 16x16 pixels. It is also used to decorate
					OpenSearch Browser search entries.
					(default 'images/favicon.ico').
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_logo_image</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Path to the logo image relative to MantisBT root folder (default 'images/mantis_logo.gif').</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_logo_url</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>The default URL to be associated with the logo.  By default this is set to $g_default_home_page (which defaults to My View page). Clicking on the logo from any page in the bug tracker will navigate to the URL specified in this configuration option.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_show_project_menu_bar</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This option specifies whether to add menu at the top of the
					page which includes links to all the projects. The default value is
					OFF.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_show_assigned_names</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>When a bug is assigned then replace the word &quot;assigned&quot; with
					the name of the developer in parenthesis. Default is ON.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_show_priority_text</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Specifies whether to show priority as text (ON) or icon
					(OFF) in the view all bugs page. Default is OFF (icon).
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_priority_significant_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Define the priority level at which a bug becomes
					significant. Significant bugs are displayed with
					emphasis. Set this value to -1 to disable the feature.
					The default value is HIGH.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_severity_significant_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Define the severity level at which a bug becomes
					significant. Significant bugs are displayed with
					emphasis. Set this value to -1 to disable the feature.
					The default value is MAJOR.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_view_issues_page_columns</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This configuration option is used to select the columns to be included in the View Issues page and in which order.  If one of the column is not accessible to the logged in user, or corresponds to a disabled feature, then it will be automatically removed from the list at runtime.  Hence, the same column list may show a different set of columns based on the logged in user, the currently selected project and enabled features (e.g. sponsorship_total is only shown if the sponsorship feature is enabled).</para>
				<para>The supported columns are: selection, edit, id, project_id, reporter_id, handler_id, priority, reproducibility, projection, eta, resolution, fixed_in_version, view_state, os, os_build, build (for product build), platform, version, date_submitted, attachment_count, category, sponsorship_total, severity, status, last_updated, summary, bugnotes_count, description, steps_to_reproduce, additional_info.  As for custom fields they can be referenced by adding a 'custom_' to their name (e.g. xyz would be custom_xyz).</para>
				<para>By default the following columns are selected: selection, edit, priority, id, sponsorship_total, bugnotes_count, attachment_count, category_id, severity, status, last_updated, summary.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_print_issues_page_columns</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This configuration option is used to select the columns to be included in the Print Issues page and in which order.  See $g_view_issues_page_columns for more details about the supported fields.</para>
				<para>By default the following columns are selected: selection, priority, id, sponsorship_total, bugnotes_count, attachment_count, category_id, severity, status, last_updated, summary</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_csv_columns</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This configuration option is used to select the columns to be included in the CSV export and in which order.  See $g_view_issues_page_columns for more details about the supported fields.</para>
				<para>By default the following columns are selected: id, project_id, reporter_id, handler_id, priority, severity, reproducibility, version, build, projection, category_id, date_submitted, eta, os, os_build, platform, view_state, last_updated, summary, status, resolution, fixed_in_version, duplicate_id.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_excel_columns</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This configuration option is used to select the columns to be included in the CSV export and in which order.  See $g_view_issues_page_columns for more details about the supported fields.</para>
				<para>By default the following columns are selected: id, project_id, reporter_id, handler_id, priority, severity, reproducibility, version, build, projection, category_id, date_submitted, eta, os, os_build, platform, view_state, last_updated, summary, status, resolution, fixed_in_version, duplicate_id.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_show_bug_project_links</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Show project links when in All Projects mode. Default is
					ON.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_show_product_version</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This controls display of the product version in the
					report, view, update and print issue pages. This flag also applies
					to other product version related fields like product build, fixed in version,
					and target version.  Valid values are ON, OFF, and AUTO.
					ON for always displayed, AUTO for displayed when project has versions defined, and OFF for
					always OFF.  The default value is AUTO.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_show_version_dates_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>The access level threshold at which users will see
					the date of release for product versions. Dates will
					be shown next to the product version, target version
					and fixed in version fields. Set this threshold to
					NOBODY to disable the feature. Default value is NOBODY.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_show_realname</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This control will replace the user's userid with their
					realname. If it is set to ON, and the real name field has been
					populated, the replacement will occur. It defaults to OFF.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_show_avatar</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Show the users' avatar</para>
				<para>In addition to enabling this configuration option it is
					necessary to install an avatar plugin like the
					<ulink url="https://www.gravatar.com">Gravatar</ulink>
					plugin which is bundled out of the box.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_show_avatar_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The threshold of users for which MantisBT should show the avatar (default DEVELOPER).
					Note that the threshold is related to the user for whom the avatar is being shown,
					rather than the user who is currently logged in.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
</section>
