<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Admin_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="admin.config.issues" lang="en-US">
	<title>Issues visibility</title>
	 <para>
		By default, all issues are visible to any user within a project. To limit
		 the visibility of issues there are several mechanisms.
	</para>
	 <section id="admin.config.issues.private">
		<title>Public/Private view status</title>
		<para>
			A view status flag can be set, for an issue, to be either public or
			 private. Private issues are accesible by the user who created it,
			 and by those users that meet a threshold defined in
			 <literal>$g_private_bug_threshold</literal>.
		</para>
		<para>
			Refer to the following configuration options related to issue view
			 status configurations:
		</para>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>$g_default_bug_view_status</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						The default viewing status for the new bug (VS_PUBLIC or
						VS_PRIVATE). The default is VS_PUBLIC.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>$g_private_bug_threshold</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						The threshold for a user to be able to view any private
						issue within a project.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>$g_set_view_status_threshold</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						The threshold for a user to be able to set an issue to Private/Public.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>$g_change_view_status_threshold</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						The threshold for a user to be able to update the view status
						while updating an issue.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>

	<section id="admin.config.issues.limitedview">
		<title>Limited view configuration</title>
		<para>
			The <literal>$g_limit_view_unless_threshold</literal> option allows
			the administrator to configure access limitations for users, letting
			them view only those issues that they are involved with, i.e. if:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						They reported the issue,
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						It is assigned to them,
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Or they are monitoring the issue.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
		<para>
			This configuration option can be set individually for each project.
			 It defaults to ANYBODY, effectively disabling the limitation (i.e.
			 users can see all issues).
		</para>
		<para>
			The value for this option is an access level threshold, so that those
			 users that meet that threshold have an unrestricted view of any issue
			 in the project. A user that doesn't meet this threshold, will have
			 a restricted view of only those issues in the conditions previously
			 described.
		</para>
		<para>
			Note that this visibility does not override other restrictions as
			 <emphasis>private issues</emphasis> or <emphasis>pivate projects</emphasis>
			 user assignments.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="admin.config.issues.limitreporters">
		<title>"Limit reporters" configuration (deprecated)</title>
		<para>
			When the option <literal>$g_limit_reporters</literal> is enabled, users
			that are reporters in a project, or lower access level, are only allowed
			to see the issues they reported. Issues reported by other users are
			not accessible by them.
		</para>
		<para>
			This option is only supported for
			ALL_PROJECTS, this means that it's a global setting that affects all projects
		</para>
		<para>
			Note that the definition of <emphasis>reporter</emphasis> in this context
			is the actual access level for which a user is able to report issues, and
			is determined by <literal>$g_report_bug_threshold</literal>. Additionally,
			that threshold can have different values in each project. Being dependant
			on that threshold, the behaviour of this option is not well defined when
			the reporting threshold is configured as discrete values with gaps, instead
			of a simple threshold. In that scenario, the visibilty is determined by
			the minimum access level contained in the <literal>$g_report_bug_threshold</literal>
			access levels array.
		</para>
		<note>
			<para>
				This option option is deprecated in favour of
				<literal>$g_limit_view_unless_threshold</literal>. The new option
				will be available by default on new installations, or after disabling
				<literal>$g_limit_reporters</literal> if enabled in an existing instance.
			</para>

		</note>
	</section>

</section>
