<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
 <!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Admin_Guide.ent">
]>
<section id="admin.config.misc">
	<title>Misc</title>

	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_user_login_valid_regex</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The regular expression to use when validating new user login names.
					The default regular expression allows a-z, A-Z, 0-9, +, -, dot, space and
					underscore.  If you change this, you may want to update the
					ERROR_USER_NAME_INVALID string in the language files to explain
					the rules you are using on your site.
				</para>
				<para>
					See <ulink url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regular_Expression">Wikipedia</ulink> for more
					details about regular expressions.  For testing regular expressions, use
					<ulink url="https://rubular.com/">Rubular</ulink>.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_monitor_bug_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Access level needed to monitor issues.
					The default value is REPORTER.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_show_monitor_list_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Access level needed to show the list of users monitoring
					an issue.
					The default value is DEVELOPER.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_monitor_add_others_bug_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Access level needed to add other users to the list of
					users monitoring an issue.
					The default value is DEVELOPER.
				</para>
				<para>This setting should not be lower than
					<emphasis>$g_show_monitor_list_threshold</emphasis>.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_monitor_delete_others_bug_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Access level needed to delete other users from the
					list of users monitoring an issue.
					The default value is DEVELOPER.
				</para>
				<para>This setting should not be lower than
					<emphasis>$g_show_monitor_list_threshold</emphasis>.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_allow_reporter_close</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Allow reporters to close the bugs they reported.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_delete_bug_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Allow the specified access level and above to delete
					bugs.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_move_access_level</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Allow the specified access level and above to move bugs
					between projects.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_allow_account_delete</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Allow users to delete their own accounts.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_allow_anonymous_login</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Enable anonymous access to Mantis. You must also
					specify $g_anonymous_account as the account which
					anonymous users will browse Mantis with. The default
					setting is OFF.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_anonymous_account</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Define the account which anonymous users will assume
					when using Mantis. This account is considered by Mantis
					to be protected from modification. In other words, this
					account can only be modified by users with an access
					level equal to or higher than $g_manage_user_threshold.
					Anonymous users will not be able to adjust preferences
					or change account settings like normal users can.
				</para>
				<para>You will need to create a new account to use for this
					$g_anonymous_account setting. When creating the account
					you should specify a password, email address and so
					forth in the same way you'd create any other account.
					It is suggested that the access level for this account
					be set to VIEWER or some other read only level.
				</para>
				<para>The anonymous user account will not receive standard
					notifications and can not monitor issues.
				</para>
				<para>The default setting is blank/undefined. You only need
					to define this setting when $g_allow_anonymous_login
					is set to ON.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_link_tag</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>If a number follows this tag it will create a link to a
					bug. Default is '#'.
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>'#': a link would be #45</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>'bug:' a link would be bug:98</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bugnote_link_tag</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>If a number follows this tag it will create a link to a
					bug note. Default is '~'.
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>'~': a link would be ~45</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>'bugnote:' a link would be bugnote:98</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_enable_project_documentation</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Specifies whether to enable support for project documents or
					not. Default is OFF.  This feature is deprecated and is expected
					to be moved to a plugin in the future.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_admin_site_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Threshold at which a user is considered to be a site
					administrator. These users have the highest level of
					access to your Mantis installation. This access level
					is required to change key Mantis settings (such as
					server paths) and perform other administrative duties.
					You may need to change this value from the default of
					ADMINISTRATOR if you have defined a new access level
					to replace the default ADMINISTRATOR level in
					constant_inc.php.
				</para>
				<warning>
					<para>This is a potentially dangerous configuration
						option. Users at or above this threshold value will
						have permission to all aspects of Mantis including
						the admin/ directory. With this access level, users
						can damage your installation of Mantis, destroy
						your database or have elevated access to your
						server.
					</para>
					<para>DO NOT CHANGE THIS VALUE UNLESS YOU ABSOLUTELY
						KNOW WHAT YOU'RE DOING. BE VERY CAREFUL WITH
						CHANGING THIS CONFIGURATION VALUE FROM THE DEFAULT
						SETTING.
					</para>
				</warning>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_manage_configuration_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>The threshold required for users to be able to manage configuration of a project.
					This includes workflow, email notifications, columns to view, and others.  Default is MANAGER.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_view_configuration_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Threshold for users to view the raw system configurations as stored in the database.
					The default value is ADMINISTRATOR.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_set_configuration_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Threshold for users to set the system configurations
					generically via MantisBT web interface.
					The default value is ADMINISTRATOR.
				</para>
				<warning>
					<para>Users who have access to set configuration via the
						interface MUST be trusted. This is due to the fact that
						these users can leverage the interface to
						<emphasis>inject PHP code</emphasis> into the system,
						which is a potential security risk.
					</para>
				</warning>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
</section>
