<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
 <!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Admin_Guide.ent">
]>
<section id="admin.config.security">
	<title>Security and Cryptography</title>

	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>Content Security Policy</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Amongst other things, MantisBT relies on
					<ulink url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_Security_Policy">
						Content Security Policy</ulink> (CSP), which is a
					<ulink url="https://www.w3.org/TR/CSP/">
						W3C candidate recommendation</ulink>
					improving the system's security against
					<ulink url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_scripting">
						cross-site scripting (XSS)</ulink>
					and other, similar types of attacks.
					It is  currently supported in
					<ulink url="https://caniuse.com/#feat=contentsecuritypolicy">
						recent versions of many browsers</ulink>.
				</para>
				<note>
					<para>CSP may cause issues in certain situations (e.g.
						during development), or when using plugins relying on
						externally hosted resources such as images or scripts.
					</para>
				</note>
				<para>MantisBT currently does not provide any mechanism for
					plugins to notify the Core of 'safe' external domains.
					Because of that, even though it is not recommended for
					obvious security reasons, you may wish to disable CSP.
					You can do so by specifying a <emphasis>Custom Header</emphasis>
					in your <literal>config_inc.php</literal> file
					(see <xref linkend="admin.config.webserver" />).
				</para>
				<warning>
					<para>Disabling Content Security Policy is a security risk !
					</para>
				</warning>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>

		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_crypto_master_salt</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Master salt value used for cryptographic hashing
					throughout MantisBT. This value must be kept secret at
					all costs. You must generate a unique and random salt
					value for each installation of MantisBT you control.
					The minimum length of this string must be at least 16
					characters.
				</para>
				<para>The value you select for this salt should be a long
					string generated using a secure random number
					generator. An example for Linux systems is:
				</para>
<programlisting>
cat /dev/urandom | head -c 64 | base64
</programlisting>
				<para>Note that the number of bits of entropy per byte of
					output from /dev/urandom is not 8. If you're
					particularly paranoid and don't mind waiting a long
					time, you could use /dev/random to get much closer to
					8 bits of entropy per byte. Moving the mouse
					(if possible) while generating entropy via /dev/random
					will greatly improve the speed at which /dev/random
					produces entropy.
				</para>
				<para>This setting is blank by default. MantisBT will not
					operate in this state. Hence you are forced to change
					the value of this configuration option.
				</para>
				<warning>
					<para>This configuration option has a profound
						impact on the security of your MantisBT
						installation. Failure to set this configuration
						option correctly could lead to your MantisBT
						installation being compromised. Ensure that this
						value remains secret. Treat it with the same
						security that you'd treat the password to your
						MantisDB database.
					</para>
				</warning>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
</section>
