<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
 <!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Admin_Guide.ent">
]>
<section id="admin.config.status">
	<title>Status Settings</title>

	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_submit_status</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Status to assign to the bug when submitted. Default value is
					NEW_.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_assigned_status</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Status to assign to the bug when assigned. Default value is
					ASSIGNED.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_reopen_status</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Status to assign to the bug when reopened. Default value is
					FEEDBACK.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_feedback_status</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Status to assign to the bug when feedback is required from the issue reporter.
					Once the reporter adds a note the status moves back from feedback to $g_bug_assigned_status
					or $g_bug_submit_status based on whether the bug assigned or not.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_reassign_on_feedback</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					When a note is added to a bug currently in $g_bug_feedback_status, and the note
					author is the bug's reporter, this option will automatically set the bug status
					to $g_bug_submit_status or $g_bug_assigned_status if the bug is assigned to a
					developer.  Default value is ON.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_duplicate_resolution</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Default resolution to assign to a bug when it is
					resolved as being a duplicate of another issue.
					Default value is DUPLICATE.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_reopen_resolution</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Resolution to assign to the bug when reopened. Default value
					is REOPENED.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_auto_set_status_to_assigned</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Automatically set status to $g_bug_assigned_status whenever
					a bug is assigned to a person. Installations where assigned status
					is to be used when the defect is in progress, rather than just put
					in a person's queue should set it to OFF. Default is ON.
					For the status change to be effective, these conditions must be met:
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>Bug has no handler, and a new handler is selected</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>The assignment is not part of a explicit status change</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Current bug status is lower than defined "assigned" status</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>"Assigned" status is reachable by workflow configuration</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
					If the conditions are not met, the assignment is still made, but status will not be modified.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_resolved_status_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Bug is resolved, ready to be closed or reopened. In some
					custom installations a bug maybe considered as resolved when it is
					moved to a custom (FIXED OR TESTED) status.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_resolution_fixed_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Threshold resolution which denotes that a bug has
					been resolved and successfully fixed by developers.
					Resolutions above and including this threshold and below
					$g_bug_resolution_not_fixed_threshold are considered
					to be resolved successfully. Default value is FIXED.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_resolution_not_fixed_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Threshold resolution which denotes that a bug has
					been resolved without being successfully fixed by
					developers. Resolutions above this threshold are
					considered to be resolved in an unsuccessful way.
					Default value is UNABLE_TO_REPRODUCE.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>
				$g_bug_readonly_status_threshold $g_update_readonly_bug_threshold
			</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Bug becomes readonly if its status is &gt;=
					$g_bug_readonly_status_threshold. The bug becomes read/write again
					if re-opened and its status becomes less than this threshold. The
					default is RESOLVED. Once the bug becomes readonly, a user with an
					access level greater than or equal to
					$g_update_readonly_bug_threshold can still edit the bug.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_status_enum_workflow</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>'status_enum_workflow' defines the workflow, and reflects a
					simple 2-dimensional matrix. For each existing status, you define
					which statuses you can go to from that status, e.g. from NEW_ you
					might list statuses '10:new,20:feedback,30:acknowledged' but not
					higher ones.The default is no workflow, where all states are
					accessible from any others.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_report_bug_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This is the access level required to open a bug. The default
					is REPORTER.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_update_bug_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This is the access level generally required to update the
					content of a bug. The default is UPDATER.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_handle_bug_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This is the access level generally required to be access
					level needed to be listed in the assign to field. The default is
					DEVELOPER. If a more restrictive setting can be determined from
					$g_set_status_threshold, it will be used.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_update_bug_status_threshold $g_set_status_threshold
			</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>These settings control the access level required to promote
					a bug to a new status once the bug is
					opened.$g_set_status_threshold is an array indexed by the status
					value that allows a distinct setting for each status. It defaults
					to blank.If the appropriate status is not defined above,
					$g_update_bug_status_threshold is used instead. The default is
					DEVELOPER.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bugnote_user_edit_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Threshold at which a user can edit his/her own
					bugnotes. The default value is equal to the
					configuration setting $g_update_bugnote_threshold.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bugnote_user_delete_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Threshold at which a user can delete his/her own
					bugnotes. The default value is equal to the
					configuration setting $g_delete_bugnote_threshold.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bugnote_user_change_view_state_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Threshold at which a user can change the view status
					of his/her own bugnotes. The default value is equal to
					the configuration setting $g_change_view_status_threshold.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_allow_reporter_reopen</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>If set, the bug reporter is allowed to reopen their own bugs
					once resolved, regardless of their access level. This allows the
					reporter to disagree with the resolution. The default is
					ON.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_allow_parent_of_unresolved_to_close</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>If set, no check is performed on the status of a bug's children,
					which allows the parent to be closed whether or not the children
					have been resolved. The default is OFF.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_readonly_status_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Bug becomes readonly if its status is >= this status.  The bug becomes
					read/write again if re-opened and its status becomes less than this
					threshold.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_bug_closed_status_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Bug is closed.  In some custom installations a bug may be considered as
					closed when it is moved to a custom (COMPLETED or IMPLEMENTED) status.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>

	<para>See also:
		<xref linkend="admin.customize.status"/>
	</para>
</section>
