<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
 <!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Admin_Guide.ent">
]>
<section id="admin.config.summary">
	<title>Summary</title>

	<para>These are the settings that are used to configuration
		options related to the Summary page. This page contains statistics
		about the bugs in MantisBT.
	</para>
	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_reporter_summary_limit</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Limit how many reporters to show in the summary page. This
					is useful when there are dozens or hundreds of reporters. The
					default value is 10.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_date_partitions</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>An array of date lengths to count bugs by (in days) for the
					summary by date. The default is to count for 1, 2, 3, 7, 30, 60,
					90, 180, and 365.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_summary_category_include_project</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Specifies whether category names should be preceded by
					project names (eg: [Project] Category) when the summary page is
					viewed for all projects. This is useful in the case where category
					names are common across projects. The default is OFF.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_view_summary_threshold</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Specifies the access level required to view the summary
					page. Default is VIEWER.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_severity_multipliers</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>An array of multipliers which are used to determine
					the effectiveness of reporters based on the severity of
					bugs. Higher multipliers will result in an increase in
					reporter effectiveness. The default multipliers are:
					<programlisting>
$g_severity_multipliers = array ( FEATURE =&gt; 1,
                                  TRIVIAL =&gt; 2,
                                  TEXT =&gt; 3,
                                  TWEAK =&gt; 2,
                                  MINOR =&gt; 5,
                                  MAJOR =&gt; 8,
                                  CRASH =&gt; 8,
                                  BLOCK =&gt; 10 );
</programlisting>
					The keys of the array are severity constants from
					constant_inc.php or from custom_constants_inc.php if
					you have custom severities defined. The values are
					integers, typically in the range of 0 to 10. If you
					would like for a severity to not count towards
					effectiveness, set the value to 0 for that severity.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_resolution_multipliers</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>An array of multipliers which are used to determine
					the effectiveness of reporters based on the resolution
					of bugs. Higher multipliers will result in a decrease
					in reporter effectiveness. The only resolutions that
					need to be defined here are those which match or exceed
					$g_bug_resolution_not_fixed_threshold. The default
					multipliers are:
					<programlisting>
$g_resolution_multipliers = array( UNABLE_TO_DUPLICATE =&gt; 2,
                                   NOT_FIXABLE =&gt; 1,
                                   DUPLICATE =&gt; 3,
                                   NOT_A_BUG =&gt; 5,
                                   SUSPENDED =&gt; 1,
                                   WONT_FIX =&gt; 1 );
</programlisting>
					The keys of the array are resolution constants from
					constant_inc.php or from custom_constants_inc.php if
					you have custom resolutions defined. Resolutions not
					included here will be assumed to have a multiplier
					value of 0. The values are integers, typically in the
					range of 0 to 10. If you would like for a resolution to
					not count towards effectiveness, set the value to 0 for
					that resolution or remove it from the array completely.
					Note that these resolution multipliers are stacked on
					top of the severity multipliers. Therefore by default,
					a user reporting many duplicate bugs at severity level
					BLOCK will be far worse off than a user reporting many
					duplicate bugs at severity level FEATURE.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>

</section>

