<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
 <!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Admin_Guide.ent">
]>
<section id="admin.config.uploads">
	<title>File Upload</title>

	<para>MantisBT allows users to upload file attachments and
		associate them with bugs as well as projects. Bug attachments /
		project documents can be uploaded to the webserver or database.
		When bugs are uploaded to the webserver they are
		uploaded to the path that is configured in the project
		properties. In case of problems getting the file upload feature to
		work, check the following resources:
		<ulink url="https://www.php.net/manual/en/features.file-upload.php">PHP
			Manual
		</ulink>
		.
	</para>

	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_allow_file_upload</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Whether to allow/disallow uploading of attachments. Default
					value is ON.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_file_upload_method</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Specify the location for uploading attachments.
					In case of DISK methods you need to provide the
					webserver with write access rights to the configured upload path
					(configured in the project) and temporary upload path (used by
					PHP).
				</para>
				<para>Values: DISK or DATABASE
				</para>
				<para>Default: DATABASE
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_dropzone_enabled</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Whether to enable/disable drag and drop zone for uploading of attachments.
					Default value is ON.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_file_upload_max_num</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Maximum number of files that can be uploaded simultaneously.
					Default value is 10.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_max_file_size</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Maximum file size that can be uploaded.
					Default value is about 5 MiB.
					The maximum size is also affected by the PHP options
					post_max_size (default 8 MiB), upload_max_filesize (default 2 MiB)
					and memory_limit (default 128 MiB) specified in php.ini.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_allowed_files</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Files that are allowed. Separate items by commas. eg.
					&quot;zip,bmp,gif,jpg,txt&quot; If $g_allowed_files is filled in NO other
					file types will be allowed. If empty it will assume any files are
					accepted that pass the $g_disallowed_files list.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_disallowed_files</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Files that are not allowed. Separate items by commas. eg.
					&quot;php,php3,phtml,html,class,java,exe,pl&quot; $g_disallowed_files takes
					precedence over $g_allowed_files.
					It is recommended to disable all extensions that can be executed by
					your server.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_preview_attachments_inline_max_size</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>This limit applies to previewing of image / text attachments.
					If the attachment size is smaller than the specified value, the attachment
					is previewed with the issue details.  The previewing can be disabled
					by setting this configuration to 0.  The default value is 256 * 1024 (256KB).
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_preview_text_extensions</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>An array of file extensions (not including dots) for text files that can be previewed inline.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_preview_image_extensions</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>An array of file extensions (not including dots) for image files that can be previewed inline.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_fileinfo_magic_db_file</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Specify the filename of the magic database file.
					This is used by PHP to guess what the MIME type of a
					file is. Usually it is safe to leave this setting as the
					default (blank) as PHP is usually able to find this file
					by itself.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_file_download_xsendfile_enabled</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Enable support for sending files to users via a more efficient
					X-Sendfile method. HTTP server software supporting this technique
					includes Lighttpd, Cherokee, Apache with mod_xsendfile and nginx.
					You may need to set the proceeding file_download_xsendfile_header_name
					option to suit the server you are using.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>$g_file_download_xsendfile_header_name</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>The name of the X-Sendfile header to use. Each server tends to
					implement this functionality in a slightly different way and thus
					the naming conventions for the header differ between each server.
					Lighttpd from v1.5, Apache with mod_xsendfile and Cherokee web
					servers use X-Sendfile. nginx uses X-Accel-Redirect and Lighttpd
					v1.4 uses X-LIGHTTPD-send-file.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>

</section>
